Guide to the Yale Collection of American Literature Letter Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- "E"
  - EVANS, ALICE MARY (Box 9, Folder 345)
    - Typewritten copies of four poems, each signed in her hand: Busy Hands To a Bird Killed on the Highway To Fortress Marion Youth's Problem Solved
      Removed from: a copy of her And Did You Wonder, New Haven, 1927
  - EVANS, AUGUSTA J. (AUGUSTA JANE), 1835-1909 (Box 9, Folder 346)
    - Quotation, "selected from At the Mercy of Tiberius," with her signature. Dated Mobile, 1888 February 16
  - EVANS, FLORENCE (WILKINSON), MRS., 1878- (Box 9, Folder 347)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Unadilla Forks, N. Y., 1906 July 24
      Removed from: a copy of her A Far Country, N. Y., 1906
  - EVERETT, CHARLES CARROLL, 1829-1900 (Box 9, Folder 348)
    - ALS to an unidentified recipient, Cambridge, Mass., 1889 November 28
  - EVERETT, EDWARD, 1794-1865, 6 (Box 8, Folder 349-354)
    - ALS to S. E. Sewall, Charlesto[w]n, 1835 August 31
      Removed from: Za copy of his An oration delivered on the battlefield of Gettysburg...N. Y., 1863
    - ALS to George Peabody, Bangor, Maine, 1857 August 10
      Removed from: Za copy of his Speech in honor of Peabody...Boston, 1857
    - ALS to Professor Lovering, Boston, 1858 November 17
      Removed from: Za copy of his Mount Vernon papers, N. Y., 1860
    - ALS to Dr. J. P. Thompson, Boston, 1864 December 3
      Removed from: Za copy of A memorial of Edward Everett from the City of Boston, 1865
    - ALS to W. C. Wilde, Boston, 1852 July 17
    - ALS to Rev. Appleton, president of Bowdoin College, Boston, 1815 January 8
      Removed from: Za copy of his Defence of Christianity...Boston, 1814
    - ALS to [Dolly Madison][,] Cambridge, 1848 June 1
      Removed from: Za copy of his Address at the dinner to Prince Napoleon... Cambridge, 1861
    - ALS to Lord Radstock, 1859 January 3
      Removed from: Za copy of his Inauguration of Washington University ...Boston, St. Louis, 1857
    - ALS to President Theodore D. Woolsey, Cambridge, 1847 January 23
      Removed from: Za copy of his Orations ...v. 2. Boston, 1850
    - ALS to E. C. Bacon, Taymouth Castle, Perthshire, 1844 September 5
      Gift of Francis B. Trowbridge, August 1927
      [Transferred from RBR September. 1950]
    - ALS to Capt. Goodwin, Boston, 1861 February 25
      Regarding a begging letter from one W. Stuart, addressed to Everett, dated Boston, February 24, 1861, and attached to Everett's letter
      Gift of Mrs. Keyes Winter and Howard Huntington, April 23, 1931
    - ALS to J. E. Thayer, 32 Summer Street, 1851 December 3
    - ALS to R. C. Winthrop, Cambridge, 1849 December 1
      With ANS at end by Edward E(verett) Hale dated February 12, 1885
    - ALS to President Woolsey, Cambridge, 1850 July 30
    - 2 autographs, mounted on sheet, undated
    - ALS to Robert Bonner, n.p., 1863 December 17
    - ALS to Chauncey Allen Goodrich, Cambridge, Mass., 1847 March 17
    - ALS to "Dear Sir", [Washington, D. C.], Monday p. m.
    - Autograph card inscribed to Henry Barnard, Boston, Mass., 1858 June 24
    - ALS to John White Webster, Cambridge, Mass., 1846 May 2
      Announcing the "semi-annual visitation of the University by
      a Committee of the Overseers" for the following day. Everett became president of Harvard in 1846. White was professor of chemistry and mineralogy at Harvard at this time.
    - ALS to Col. H(enry) K(emble) Oliver, Boston, Mass., 1838 June 18
      Regretting that he cannot be present to celebrate the 4th of
      July with the Whigs of Salem but sending a message to be read.
      Purchased from C. S. Moeller
    - ALS to "Dear Sir", Charlestown, Mass., 1830 October 27
- "F"
  - FADIMAN, CLIFTON, 1904- (Box 9, Folder 355)
    - Reviews of 9 books listed below: typewritten copies with ms corrections
      17 pages
      The city of trembling leaves, by W. V. T. Clark A Texan in England, by J. F. Dobie
      Against these three, by Stuart Cloete
      One world or none, ed. by Dexter
      Masters and Katharine Way
      The education of a correspondent, by H. L. Matthews
      The white tower, by J. R. Ullman
      Bones of contention, by R. G.
      Vansittart, 1st baron Vansittart
      The hucksters, by Frederic Wakeman
      New worlds in medicine, ed. by Harold Ward
      Gift of the Book-of-the-Month club, April 1945
  - FARRAND, HIRAM AUGUSTUS (Box 9, Folder 356)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Phila., 1899 April 8
  - FARRAR, GERALDINE, 1882-1967 (Box 9, Folder 357)
    - 2 ALS to Mrs. Gerardus P. Herrick, Ridgefield, Conn., 1946, 1951
      With 1 envelope
  - FARRAR, JOHN CHIPMAN, 1896- (Box 9, Folder 358)
    - Dabney, Virginius, 1901-. TLS to John (Chipman) Farrar, Richmond, Va., 1948 November 9
    - Freeman, D. S. TLS to John (Chipman) Farrar, Richmond, Va., 1948 November 10
    - Carbon copy of TL to Jim Jenkins, Jr., 1948 November 24
      Gift of John Chipman Farrar, 1949
    - Hamilton, Charles Henry. TLS to John (Chipman) Farrar, Richmond, Va., 1948 December 1
      With carbon of reply, 1 leaf
  - FAULKNER, VIRGINIA, 1913- (Box 9, Folder 359)
    - TLS to the Librarian of Yale University. Wilton, Conn., 1944 January 15
      From the Library files, January 1944
  - FAWCETT, EDGAR, 1847-1904, 4 (Box 9, Folder 360-363)
    - ALS giving autobiographical and bibliographical data, 22 W. 17th St., N. Y., [1884] April 18
      7 pages (2 leaves)
    - ALS to Messrs. Stone and Kimball, New York, N. Y., September 12
    - ALS to an unidentified correspondent, New York, N. Y., August 26
      Refusing to allow his verse to be printed in an anthology. Recipient possibly Mrs. Holloway, to whom a letter from Rebecca Harding Davis occurred in this same lot of ms
      letters
    - ALS to an unidentified correspondent, New York, N. Y., April 22
    - ALS to an unidentified correspondent, New York, N. Y., [1879] July 6
      Offering to write a review of William Henry Bishop's Detmold (1879)
    - 2 ALS to Robert Bonner, New York, N. Y.
      Concerning his serial story apparently published in the New York Ledger under the pseudonym Karl Drury. Pencil note on second letter identifies recipient as Bonner
    - ALS to Henry Chandler Bowen, New York, N. Y., [1888] December 11
      Concerns his poem "The Young Samson" Poem published in volume London, 1889; hence guess as to date (i.e. year)
    - 2 ALS to Robert Underwood Johnson, New York, N. Y., February, July
      31 page
      Purchased, Hamilton
    - ALS to Victor (Gustave) Plarr, London, Eng., January 7
      Gift of Robert F. Metzdorf, June 10, 1955
    - ALS to "Dear Bishop," [New York], Saturday morn., undated
      Gift of G. R. Sattig, 1948
    - Bigotry, Autograph ms of 12 stanzas of verse
      Removed from: Za copy of his Short poems...N. Y., 1872
    - ALS. 22 W. 17th St., New York, February 2
    - Lilacs [poem], AMS, dated New York, 1887 April
      8 lines
      On conjugate leaf: "The twilight of the poets" [poem] (catalogued separately)
      Gift of Philip M. Neufeld, 1961
    - The Twilight of the Poets ("To E(dmund) C(larence) S[tedman] on Reading his Poets of America") [poem]. AMS
      6 lines. On conjugate leaf of his poem "Lilacs"
    - 2 ALS to Bliss Carman, New York, N. Y., [1895] July, December
      Gift of James T. Babb, 1959. 1st letter refers to his "Songs of Joy" in the Chap-Book. His "Little Lyrics of Joy" appeared in Chap-Book beginning 1 March 1895
  - FELTON, C. C. (CORNELIUS CONWAY), 1807-1862 (Box 9, Folder 364)
    - ALS to President N. F. Moore, Cambridge, 1848 January 17
      Removed from: Za copy of Addresses at the inauguration of Cornelius Conway Felton...Cambridge, 1860
    - ALS to Mr. Underwood, Cambridge, [1858] September 17
  - FERBER, EDNA, 1887-1968, 2 (Box 9, Folder 365-366)
    - TLS to James T(inkham) Babb, Stepney Depot, Conn., 1945 September 6
      Gift of Mr. Babb
    - Our Mrs. McChesney. Typescript (carbon) and (original)
      130 l. and 128 leaves
      3-act play, by Edna Ferber and George V(ere) Hobart
      Original title: Roast beef medium
  - FERRIL, THOMAS HORNSBY, 1896- (Box 9, Folder 367)
    - Harper's Ferry Floating Away: A Poem of Recognition. Typewritten ms and two sets of galley-proofs
      5 pages, 3 pages, 3 pages
  - FERRIS, MORRIS PATTERSON, MRS., 1855-1932 (Box 9, Folder 368)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Garden City, 1890 November 17
  - FERRIS, WALTER, b. 1882 (Box 9, Folder 369)
    - TLS to Jack R. Crawford, Hadlyme, Ct., Friday, undated
  - FIELD, KATE, 1838-1896 (Box 10, Folder 370)
    - ALS to "Dear Madame", New York, N. Y., 1866 October 11
  - FIELDS, ANNIE, 1834-1915, 3 (Box 10, Folder 371-373)
    - 3 ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Boston, Mass. [etc.], 1877-1884
    - ALS to John Phillips Street, Boston, Mass., 1895 March 22
      Concerning the project for a memorial to Alfred Lord Tennyson
      Enclosing clipping Gift of James T. Babb, 1959
    - 2 ALS to Mr. Ward, Cambridge, Mass., 1878 December, 1880
    - January
    - ALS to Mr. and Mrs. [Francis Hopkinson?] Smith, Boston, Mass., 1889 January 10
    - ANS to [Charlotte (Hastings)] Whipple, Manchester, Mass., 1877 August 1
      Mrs. Charlotte (Hastings) Whipple is Mrs. Edwin Percy Whipple
  - FIELDS, JAMES THOMAS, 1817-1881, 3 (Box 10, Folder 374-376)
    - To Leigh Hunt in Elysium. A Familiar Epistle: Printed text as published in an (English) newspaper, August. 1880, with corrections and additions in [ms], and with a covering ALS to the Editor of the Literary World(,) Manchester, Mass., 1880 September 18
      14 plus 2 pages, 4to and folio and 8vo
      From the Aldis Collection of Autographs
    - Address at Portsmouth, 1873: autograph [ms]
      17 pages, 4to, including verses by Mrs. Fields
    - An Epistle: From the Modern 'Essay on Man.' autograph [ms], signed "A. Pope Jr. [i.e. J. T. Fields]"
      1 page, 4to, as printed in the Boston Transcript
    - ALS to Hovey, Boston, 1878 April 5
      1 page, 16mo., enclosing AMS of his poem "The White-throated sparrow", 2 pages, 4to
    - 2 ALS to Charles Marseilles, Boston, 1874 October, 1875
    - March
      Each 2 pages, 8vo.
      [1874 letter] with addressed envelope
      Removed from: Za copy of his Yesterdays with authors, Boston, 1872
    - ALS to Charles Brooks, [Boston?], February 5
      1 page, 8 vo.
    - ALS to "Dear Percy", Boston, January 16
      1 page, 16mo.
    - ALS to "Dear E.," [n. p.] Saturday evening, undated
    - ALS to Justin Winsor, Boston, 1876 October 26
      Removed from: Za copy of his Hawthorne, Boston, 1876
    - ALS to Mr. Halleck, Boston, 1865 March 15
      1 page, 32mo.
      Recipient is certainly FitzGreen Halleck
    - ALS to E. P. Whipple, [Boston?], Thursday, undated
      Removed from: Za copy of his Poems, Cambridge [1854]
    - ALS to Childs, Boston, 1879 March 2
      Mounted on sheet with portrait signed
    - ALS. Boston, 1878 December 14
    - ALS to "Dear friend," Boston, Mass., 1879 December 3
    - ALS to "Dear Cashman," Boston, Mass., 1878 January 27
      Introducing Signora (Eliza Ostinelli) Biscaccianti, the actress
    - ALS to George Livermore, [Boston, Mass.?], 1861 July 13
      Thanking him for the gift of Oliver's Pocket Bible
    - LS to Mr. Silsbee, [Boston, Mass.?], 1868 December 21
    - ALS to Samuel Smiles, Boston, Mass., 1861 April 8
    - ALS to Bayard Taylor, Boston, Mass., 1865 January 10
      Signed with initials. With ms certification by Mrs. Fields
    - ALS to "Friend Welch," Boston, Mass., December 23
    - ALS to Bayard Taylor, Boston, Mass., 1866 May 8
      Letter mentions his Story of Kennett (1866) "J. G. W." is John Greenleaf Whittier
      Gift of Prof. Bainton, May 12, 1958
    - Dirge for a Young Girl [poem]. AMS
      16 lines
    - ALS to "Friend Griggs," Manchester-by-the-sea, Mass., 1873 September 6
  - FINDLATER, JANE HELEN, 1866-1946 (Box 10, Folder 377)
    - ALS. Ellangowan, Beer, Axminster, Devonshire, October 11
      Removed from: Van Sinderen copy of her Stones from a glass house. London, 1904
      Gift of Adrian Van Sinderen, 1940
  - FISHER, DOROTHY CANFIELD, 1879-1958, 2 (Box 10, Folder 378-379)
    - TLS to Mrs. Samuel C. Holbrook, Arlington, Vermont, 1939 April 22
      Together with typed note signed by her secretary, Mrs. Carl Rice, returning Mrs. Holbrook's original letter
      Gift of Mrs. S. C. Holbrook, May 1939
    - ALS to Mrs. George Pierce Baker, Poughkeepsie, N. Y., undated [1926]
    - Reviews of 13 books listed below: typewritten copies with [ms] corrections [3 signed]
      20 p.
      They seek a city, by Arna Bontemps and Jack Conroy
      Tell the people, by Pearl Buck
      Men at work, by Stuart Chase
      Minerals of might, by W. O. Hotchkiss
      Dark medallion, by Dorothy Langley
      Edward Bellamy, by A. E. Morgan
      Pride's way, by Robert Molloy
      They changed their skies, by L. P. Osborne
      The knights of the Cape, by Ricardo Palma
      The charity ball, by Jessie Scott
      The pattern of Soviet power, by Edgar Snow
      States of grace, by Frances Steegmuller
      Delta wedding, by Eudora Welty
      Gift of the Book-of-the-Month-club, April 1945
  - FISKE, HORACE SPENCER, 1859-1940 (Box 10, Folder 380)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Chicago, 1903 November 2
      Removed from: his Chicago in picture and poetry, [Chicago]1903.
      Za.F546.903p
  - FITCH, CLYDE, 1865-1909, 2 (Box 10, Folder 381-382)
    - ALS to Mrs. Benjamin I. Nesmith, [New York, N. Y.], 1894 February 23
    - Glad of It. Typescript (carbon)
      194 leaves
      4-act play
  - FITZGERALD, F. SCOTT (FRANCIS SCOTT), 1896-1940, 4 (Box 10, Folder 383-386)
    - Crazy Sunday. Typewritten ms (original) [and photocopy]
      25 numbered leaves each
      As printed in The American Mercury, with ms corrections by the author and by H(enry) L(ouis) Mencken
    - Goodman, Aubrey (Louis). The Great Gatsby: A Musical Play Adapted from the Novel...Book and Lyrics by Aubrey Goodman; Music by Robert Morgan
      [81] l.
      Reproduced from typewritten copy
      Without the music
      Produced by Yale Dramat 1956 May 3- June 9
      Gift of Professor Pearson
    - 2 ALS to Henry Albert Phillips, Bas Pyrenees and Nice
      Gift of Carroll Alton Means, October 1951
  - FOLEY, PATRICK KEVIN, 1856-1937 (Box 10, Folder 387)
    - TLS to Frank Maier, Boston, Mass., 1903 September 23
  - FOLSOM, FLORENCE, b. 1860- (Box 10, Folder 388)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Upper Montclair, N. J., 1899 August 6
  - FORD, JULIA ELLSWORTH, 1859-1950 (Box 10, Folder 389)
    - The Beloved Stranger, an autograph poem
    - Little Book of Prayers, an autograph poem
  - FOX, JOHN, 1863?-1919, 2 (Box 10, Folder 390-391)
    - 2 ALS to Owen F. Aldis, Big Stone Gap, Va. and Near Ogden, 1904 February 5, 22
      4 pages and 3 pages
      Removed from: Za copy of his Blue-grass and rhododendron, N. Y., 1901; and his Crittenden, N. Y., 1900
    - ALS to Harper and Bros. (Harper, firm, publishers, New York; 1897 Harper and brothers), Big Stone Gap, Va., 1897 August 4
  - FRANK, WALDO DAVID, 1889-1967 (Box 10, Folder 392)
    - TLS to [Gorham B.] Munson, [New York, N. Y.], 1936 January 28
    - TLS to John McClure, New York, N. Y., 1922 April 19
  - FRANKENBERG, LLOYD, 1907- (Box 10, Folder 393)
    - My Peace with the World (Part I, Sections IV-X). Typescript (original)
      89 leaves
      An autobiographical poem Laid in before Section VIII is an ALS to Carl Van Vechten referring to the ms.
      Gift of Carl Van Vechten, 1960
  - FREDERIC, HAROLD, 1856-1898 (Box 10, Folder 394)
    - Autograph receipt, signed. London, Eng., 1893 July 1
      For payment from the Youth's
      Companion for serial rights to "The Deserter"
  - FREEMAN, MARY ELEANOR WILKINS, 1852-1930, 4 (Box 10, Folder 395-398)
    - ALS to Mr. Bacheller, Randolph, Mass., 1895 October 18
      Renewing her refusal of invitation to attend New England Society dinner
      Removed from: Za copy of her Comfort Pease and her gold ring, New York, [etc.] 1895
    - ALS to Mr. Bridgman, Randolph, Mass., 1894 May 29
    - ALS to Miss Guild, Randolph, Mass., 1898 May 3
    - ALS to "Dear Sirs," Randolph, Mass., 1897 October 4
    - ALS to Miss Dickinson, Vienna, Va., 1890 May 12
    - ALS to "Dear Sir," Randolph, Mass., 1899 January 25
    - 3 ALS and 1 TLS to Miss (Jeannette Leonard) Gilder, Randolph, Mass. and Metuchen, N. J., 1890-1915
      Purchased from Driscoll, October 24, 1958 ... D. G. Wing
    - 6 ALS to William H(enry) Rideing, Randolph, Mass., 1890-1898
      The first letter is addressed to "Editors, The Youth's Companion"
  - FRENCH, ALICE
    See: THANET, OCTAVE, 1850-1934
  - FRENCH, LILLIE HAMILTON, 1854-1939 (Box 11, Folder 399)
    - ALS to Mrs. Edmund Clarence (Laura Hyde (Woodworth)) Stedman, New York, April 17
  - FROHMAN, DANIEL, 1851-1940 (Box 11, Folder 400)
    - TNS to Marian King, New York, N. Y., 1927 December 24
      Gift of Marian King, June 10[?], 1958
  - FROHMAN, MARGARET (Box 11, Folder 401)
    - ALS to Mr. Pach, New York, N. Y., undated
  - FROST, ELIZABETH HOLLISTER (Box 11, Folder 402)
    - ANS to [William Rose] Benet, Nantucket Island, Mass., 1929 July 11
      Removed from: a copy of her Hovering Shadow, N. Y., 1929
      Plain funds, November 1942
  - FROST, FRANCES, 1905-1959 (Box 11, Folder 403)
    - TLS to Mrs. George Pierce Baker, New York, N. Y., 1931 November 13
  - FROST, ROBERT, 1874-1963, 4 (Box 11, Folder 404-407)
    - ALS to Edward Bliss Reed, Amherst, Massachusetts, 1917 May 24
      Gift of Dr. E. B. Reed (Libr. Assoc.), November. 1935
    - ANS to John Cournos, [London], [1928] September 21
      Southworth fund, March 1933
    - ALS to James [Raye Wells], [n. p.], 1931
      Transferred from James R. Wells collection, Rare Book Room
    - ALS [salutation cut off]. South Shaftsbury, Vt., 1931 October 6
      Sending a photograph
    - 3 ALS, with addressed envelopes, to Henry Tunis Meigs, v. p., 1915-1921
      Gift of Miss Hester Meigs, May 1944
    - Ms copies made by him of three of his poems: Blue-Butterfly Day Dust of Snow Putting in the Seed
      With his signature. [With his letters to Henry Tunis Meigs]
    - Frost, Elinor. ALS to Mme. [Albert] Feuillerat, South Shaftbury, Vt., [1928] December 17
      4 pages (1 leaf)
      From the estate of Professor Albert Feuillerat, 1953
    - Bibliography of the writings of Robert Frost up to 1929. Autograph ms
      With autograph note signed: Albert Feuillerat, Juillet 1931
    - The Airplane of Wilbur and Orville Wright, AMS of four lines of verse
  - FULLER, MARGARET, 1810-1850 (Box 11, Folder 408)
    - 2 ALS to Amelia Greenwood, [n. p.], undated
      Removed from: Za copy of her Memoirs...v. 1, Boston, 1852
    - Verse. 6 stanzas with title: Light and warmth - Schiller; Breadth and depth - Schiller, in Margaret Fuller's autograph with sheet addressed to Rev. J. S. Dwight
      Removed from: Za copy of her Memoirs...v. 2, Boston, 1852
    - Fragment of a letter, [n. p.], undated
      Removed from: Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1831.
      Conversations. Eckermann. Eng. tr. Ossoli. Conversations with Goethe in the last years of his life. Boston, 1839. Za.Os7.839g
    - ALS to Thesta Dana, Providence, 1838 May 30
      Removed from: her Woman in the nineteenth century. New York, 1845 Za.Os7.845w
    - Cheney, Ednah Dow (Littlehale), 1824-1904. ANS to Lydia M. Child, [Boston], [1870 May]
      Invitation to the festival in commemoration of Margaret Fuller's sixtieth birthday, May 23, 1870
      Removed from: Za copy of Alcott, Amos Bronson, Sonnets and canzonets ...Boston, 1882
    - Ms of two poems: "Another version of the same" "Our confidence, T. Koerner"
      Removed from: her Papers on literature and art. Za.Os7.846p
  - FULLER, RICHARD F. (Box 11, Folder 409)
    - TLS to E(ugene) F(rancis) Saxton, Boston, 1923 December 21
      Concerns the suppression of Aldous Huxley's Antic Hay by the Watch and Ward Society in Massachusetts
      Gift of Mr. and Mrs. John Farrar, November 1952
  - FURMAN, ALFRED ANTOINE, 1856- (Box 11, Folder 410)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Clifton, N. J., 1896 January 19
  - FURNESS, HORACE HOWARD, 1833-1912 (Box 11, Folder 411)
    - ALS to Alvey Augustus Adee, Wallingford, Pa., 1895 September 11
  - FURNESS, WILLIAM HENRY, 1802-1896 (Box 11, Folder 412)
    - Bartol, Cyrus Augustus (1813-1900). ANS to Florence, Boston, 1875 April 9
      Removed from: Za copy of Alcott, Amos Bronson, Sonnets and Canzonets ...Boston, 1882
    - 2 ALS to Mr. Dwight, Philadelphia, 1867 October, December
    - Three photostatic copies of an ALS to Ralph Waldo Emerson, Philadelphia, 1854 November 26
      Gift of Henry S. Canby, November 1940
- "G"
  - GALE, ZONA, 1874-1938, 3 (Box 11, Folder 413-415)
    - 4 TLS to Devere Allen, Portage, Wisc., 1926-1938
      With one envelope
    - TLS to Mrs. Buckstaff, Portage, Wisconsin, 1925 February 12
      Removed from: Zona Gale's Friendship Village (1909) purchased with Alvord fund. call no. Za.G131.909F
    - ALS to Mr. Walker, Portage, Wisc., March 18
  - GALLAGHER, WILLIAM D. (WILLIAM DAVIS), 1808-1894 (Box 11, Folder 416)
    - Our Early Days, Original ms poem
      Printed in his Selections from the poetical literature of the West (1841), p. 65-67
      Removed from: Aldis copy of his Selections (1841). Call no.:
      Za.G.135.841.copy 2
  - GARDNER, NELSON (Box 11, Folder 417)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Rutherford, N. J., 1907 August 26
  - GARLAND, HAMLIN, 1860-1940, 2 (Box 11, Folder 418-419)
    - 5 ALS, 2 APCS to Herbert Stuart Stone, New York, 1893-1894
      Removed from: Za copies of his Main- travelled roads, Boston, 1891 and 1893; his Prairie songs, Cambridge, 1893; and his Prairie folks, Chicago, 1893 and 1894
      Gifts of Owen F. Aldis, 1911
    - ALS. 474 Elm St., Chicago, 1894 December 24
    - ALS. West Salem, Wis., 1896 September 12
      Removed from: Za copy of his Life of U.S. Grant. N. Y., 1898
    - ALS to "Dear Friends," West Salem, Wis., 1894 August 30
      Removed from: Za copy of his Main-travelled roads, Boston, 1891
    - Main-travelled roads: 1 page of ms printer's copy numbered p. 15 and signed; 6 lines of directions to the printer
    - Fragment of a letter, Boston, 1893 December 16
      Removed from: Za copy of his Crumbling Idols. Cambridge, 1894
    - Crumbling Idols: contents page in Garland's hand
    - Prairie Folks: 5 sheets of miscellaneous page-proofs for the 2nd edition, Chicago, 1894, of this book
      Removed from: Za copy of his Prairie Folks, Chicago, 1894
    - ALS to "Dear Friend" [Mary E(leanor) (Wilkins) Freeman], West Salem, Wisc., [1894] June 24
      With a signed card
      Letter refers to her Pembroke (1894)
  - GARRISON, THEODOSIA PICKERING, 1874-1944, 2 (Box 11, Folder 420-421)
    - ANS to Mrs. Arthur T. Aldis, New York, N. Y., undated
      Removed from: Mrs. Aldis's Autograph book
      Gift of Mrs. Arthur T. Aldis, October 1934
    - ALS to Mr. White, New York, N. Y., 1907 June 19
      Complying with a request for an autograph
  - GARRISON, WILLIAM LLOYD, 1805-1879 (Box 11, Folder 422)
    - ALS to Theodore Roosevelt, Boston, 1871 January 10
      Removed from: Za copy of The Unity of Italy, the American celebration. N. Y., 1871
  - GELLATLY, FRANCIS (Box 11, Folder 423)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Evanston, Ill., 1886 February 5
  - GIBSON, ROBERT EDWARD LEE, 1864- (Box 11, Folder 424)
    - ALS to M. S. McKinney, [secretary to E. C. Stedman?], St. Louis, Mo., 1895 September 30
  - GIBSON, W. HAMILTON (WILLIAM HAMILTON), 1850-1896 (Box 11, Folder 425)
    - ALS to Mr. Hurd, N. Y., 1880 April 23
      Removed from: Za copy of his Pastoral days...N. Y., 1881
  - GIFFORD, FANNIE STEARNS DAVIS, b. 1884
    See: DAVIS, FANNIE STEARNS, b. 1884
  - GILDER, RICHARD WATSON, 1844-1909, 7 (Box 11, Folder 426-432)